Serge Diaghilev/Serge Lifar Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- I. Printed Music Material, 1750-1950 (Box 1-67)
  - A. General (Box 1-65)
    - Rimskiĭ-Korsakov, Nikolaĭ Andreevich
      - La Pskovitaine: Ouverture, entr'actes. [=Pskovitianka.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, n.d., Arranged by Nadezhda Rimskaia-Korsakova for piano, four hands; score; 37 p.; Plate no. 6969 through 6973. (Box-folder 46/2)
      - Sadko. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1897., Full score; 569 p.; Plate no. 1430.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 46/3)
      - Sadko. [Leipzig]: [M. Belaïeff], n.d., Parts for chorus: tenors [1] p.; basses [17] p.; Plate no. 1432.; Note: parts for chorus: tenors incomplete: p. 42-43 only, basses incomplete: p. 33 through 50 (end of opera) only; Italian text inscribed in tenor part, in red ink; French text inscribed in bass part, in black ink.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 46/4)
      - Skazanie o nevidimom grade Kitezhie i dievie Fevronii. [=Legend of the invisible city of Kitezh and the maiden Fevroniia.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1906., Piano-vocal score; 326 p.; Plate no. 2613.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 47/1)
      - Skazka, op. 29. [=Conte féerique.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1886., Reduction by the composer for piano, four hands; score; 35 p.; Plate no. 19. (Box-folder 47/2)
      - Skazka o tsarie Saltanie. [=The story of Tsar Saltan.] St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', [1900]., Piano-vocal score; 281 p.; Plate no. 4849.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 47/3)
      - Skazka o tsarie Saltanie. Moscow: W. Bessel, n.d., Reduction for solo piano; score; 186 p.; Plate no. 4920.; Note: score containing vocal line indications in Russian (Box-folder 47/4)
      - Snégourotchka. [=The snow maiden.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, 1908., Piano-vocal score; 296 p.; Plate no. 6400.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/53)
      - Snegurochka: Siuita. [=The snow maiden: Suite.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, n.d., Full score; 73 p.; Plate no. 2847.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 47/5)
      - Snegurochka [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Chorus part books; 88 p.; Laid in: most items contain performance indications in pencil and/or in ink; items may also include manuscript emendations in ink.; Part books [complete in 88 p.] begin with the Choeur des oiseaux of the Prologue.; Contents of BOX: 48-51: BOX: 48/1-8 Copies 1 through 8. BOX: 49/1-8 Copies 9 through 16 of the above. BOX: 50/1-8 Copies 17 through 24 of the above. BOX: 51/1-15 Copies 25 through 39 of the above: incomplete items.; Contents of BOX: 51/1-15 Copies 25 through 30 (folders 1 through 6): p. 1-80 only Copy 31 (folder 7): p. 1-72 only Copies 32 and 33 (folders 8 and 9): p. 1-40 only Copies 34 and 35 (folders 10 and 11): p. 1-8 only Copy 36 (folder 12): p. 17-24 only Copy 37 (folder 13): p. 57-66 only Copy 38 (folder 14): p. 65-72 only Copy 39 (folder 15): p. 65-88 only. (Box-folder 48/1-8, Box-folder 49/1-8, Box-folder 50/1-8, Box-folder 51/1-15)
      - Sniegurochka. [=The snow maiden.] St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', 1881., Piano-vocal score; 298 p.; Plate no. 931 through 955.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder S/54)
      - V temnoĭ roshchie zamolk soloveĭ, op. 4, no. 3. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, [1866]., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 1072 1075.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 52/1)
    - Roberts, Lee S.
      - Smiles. Constantinople: J. d'Andria, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 453.; Language note: English (Box-folder 52/2)
    - Roger-Ducasse, Jean Jules Amable
      - Petite suite: Claironnerie. Paris: A. Durand, 1911., Arranged by J. Charlot for solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. D. & F.8145(3). (Box-folder 52/3)
      - Prélude d'un ballet. Paris: A. Durand, 1910., Arranged by the composer for solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. D. & F.7929. (Box-folder 52/4)
      - Suite française. Paris: A. Durand, 1909., Arranged by the composer for piano, four hands; score; 41 p.; Plate no. D. & F.7336. (Box-folder 52/5)
    - Romand, Gabriel and Gabriel Pachoutine
      - Mon prince charmant. Paris: Éditions musicales universelles, 1935., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. EMU 152.; Cover carries holograph inscription in pencil: Patchouine's Paris address, in Russian.; Language note: French (Box-folder 52/6)
    - Rosellen, Henri
      - Le trémolo, op. 31, no. 1. Hamburg: A.J. Benjamin, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. A.J.B.3205. (Box-folder 52/7)
    - Rosey, George
      - The honey-moon (mar[s]ch) See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68
    - Rossini, Gioacchino
      - A Grenade. [Deux nouvelles compositions, no. 1.] [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. H 35967 H.; Language note: French; Language note: Spanish (Box-folder 52/8)
      - Il barbiere di Siviglia. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 327 p.; Plate no. 41691.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 52/9)
      - Il barbiere di Siviglia. Paris: M. Schlesinger, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 208 p.; Plate no. 615.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 52/10)
      - ll barbiere di Siviglia. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 125 p.; Plate no. 41012. (Box-folder 53/1)
      - La boutique fantasque. London: J. & W. Chester, 1919., Arranged by O. Respighi for solo piano; score; 78 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.9706.; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder S/55)
      - Bruschino. [Il Signor Bruschino.] Paris: Heugel, n.d. See also: Il Signor Bruschino, Box 54, Folders 3, 4, 5, Piano-vocal score; 117 p.; Plate no. H.5727.; Language note: French (Box-folder S/32)
      - La cambiale di matrimonio. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 163 p.; Plate no. 113280.; Language note: Italian; Contains annotations in pencil; hardcover copy. (Box-folder S/33)
      - La cambiale di matrimonio. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 163 p.; Plate no. 113280.; Softcover copy.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 53/2)
      - La Cenerentola. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 354 p.; Plate no. 45707.; Contains autograph of Lifar on cover, in ink.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/34)
      - Échantillon de blague. [Péchés de vieillesse, v. 9, no. 11.] Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 46951. (Box-folder 53/3)
      - La gazzetta. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 372 p.; Plate no. 27118 through 27147.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 53/4)
      - L'italiana in Algeri. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 291 p.; Plate no. 87409.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/35)
      - L'italiana in Algeri: Sinfonia. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged by L. Cerri for small orchestra; 15 p.; Plate no. 108722.; piano part only (Box-folder 53/5)
      - L'italienne à Alger. Paris: Aulagnier, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 205 p.; Plate no. A.A.847.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil.; Language note: French (Box-folder S/36)
      - La pie voleuse. [=La gazza ladra.] Paris: Aulagnier, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 193 p.; Plate no. C.B.7.1 through 7.5; C.B.7.7 through 7.9; C.B.7.11 through 7.15.; Language note: French; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/56)
      - La pietra del parragone. Paris: Launer, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 217 p.; Plate no. 1631, 1371, 884, 2037, 1395, 1394, 1396, 1412, 1378, 1397, 1678, 1375, 1376, 1400, 1377, 435, 270, 1392.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 53/6)
      - Cinq grands quatuors. [=Sonate a quattro.] Paris: B. Schott, n.d., Parts for: vn I, vn II, vla, vc; 16 p.; 16 p.; 16 p.; 16 p.; Plate no. 2799 through 2803. (Box-folder 54/1)
      - La regata veneziana. [Péchés de vieillesse, v. 1, no. 8 through 10.] Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 31 p.; Plate no. 45844.; Language note: Italian (Venetian dialect) (Box-folder 54/2)
      - Il Signor Bruschino. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d. See also: Bruschino, Shelved item 32., Piano-vocal score; 167 p.; Plate no. 112640.; Contenst: BOX: 54/3 Copy 1 BOX: 54/4 Copy 2 of the above.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 54/3-4)
      - Il Signor Bruschino: Sinfonia. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Parts for: vn I, vn II, vla, vc/cb; 5 p.; 6 p.; 5 p.; 5 p.; Plate no. 113091 through 113094.; Parts for: vn I (6 copies, 5 p. each), vn II (5 copies, 6 p. each), vla (3 copies, 5 p. each), vc/cb (6 copies, 5 p. each). (Box-folder 54/5)
      - [S]oirée[s] musicale[s], v. 1: 8 ariette. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 51 p.; Plate no. 45768.; Language note: French; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 54/6)
      - [S]oirée[s] musicale[s], v. 2: 4 duetti. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Two voices and piano; score; 41 p.; Plate no. 45847.; Language note: French; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 54/7)
      - Le Traître démasqué. [=L'inganno felice ("L'inganno fortunato").] Brussels: E. Lauweryns, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 138 p.; Language note: French (Box-folder 55/1)
      - Il turco in Italia. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 329 p.; Plate no. 21051 through 21086.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 55/2)
    - Rubinstein, Anton
      - Ballada. Moscow: Gosudarstvennoe izdatel'stvo, Muzykal'nyĭ sektor, 1928., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 17406.; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 55/3)
    - Sablon, A.
      - Paris sur la bouche See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Saint-Saëns, Camille
      - Javotte. Paris: A. Durand, 1896., Reduction for solo piano; score; 121 p.; Plate no. D. & F.5150. (Box-folder 55/5)
      - Ascanio: Suite no. 1. Paris: A. Durand, 1919., Arranged by H. Mouton for small orchestra; 15 p.; Plate no. D. & F.9754.; piano/conductor's score only (Box-folder 55/6)
    - Salabert, Francis
      - Hawaiian butterfly. Paris: F. Salabert, 1917., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. E.A.S.1149. (Box-folder 55/7)
    - Sarrablo, M.
      - El número 13 See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Sartinskiĭ-Beĭ, D. K.
      - IA ne mogu poniat'. Moscow: N. Davingof, [1916]., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. H.1579 D.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 55/8)
    - Satie, Erik
      - Aperçus désagréables. Paris: E. Demets, 1913., Piano, four hands; score; 13 p.; Plate no. E.1740 D. (Box-folder 55/9)
      - La belle excentrique. Paris: Éditions de la sirène, 1922., Piano, four hands; score; 25 p.; Plate no. E.D.94.L.S. (Box-folder 55/10)
      - Chapitres tournés en tous sens. Paris: E. Demets, 1913., Solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. E.1113 D.; incomplete after p. 8 (Box-folder 55/11)
      - Croquis et agaceries d'un gros bonhomme en bois. Paris: E. Demets, 1913., Solo piano; score; 10 p.; Plate no. E.1789 D. (Box-folder 55/12)
      - Descriptions automatiques. Paris: E. Demets, 1913., Solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. E.1788 D. (Box-folder 55/13)
      - La diva de "L'Empire". Paris: Bellon Ponscarme, 1904., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. B.P. & Cie 901.; Language note: French (Box-folder 55/14)
      - Embryons desséchés. Paris: E. Demets, 1913., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. E.1795 D. (Box-folder 56/1)
      - En habit de cheval. Paris: Rouart, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 13 p.; Also published Paris: Lerolle, n.d.; Plate no. R.9823.L. & Cie. (Box-folder 56/2)
      - Le fils des étoiles: Préludes. Paris: E. Baudoux, n.d., Solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. E.B.et Cie 220. (Box-folder 56/3)
      - Gymnopédies, no. 3. Paris: Rouart, n.d., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Also published Paris: Lerolle, n.d.; Plate no. R.L.9840 & Cie. (Box-folder 56/4)
      - Menus propos enfantins. Paris: E. Demets, 1916., Solo piano; score; 6 p.; Plate no. E.1818 D. (Box-folder 56/5)
      - 3 morceaux en forme de poire. Paris: Rouart, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 31 p.; Also published Paris: Lerolle, n.d.; Plate no. R.L.9799 & Cie.; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 56/6)
      - Sonneries de la Rose + Croix. Paris: Rouart, n.d., Solo piano; score; 12 p.; Also published Paris: Lerolle, n.d. (Box-folder 56/7)
      - Vieux sequins et vieilles cuirasses. Paris: E. Demets, 1913., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. E.1135 D. (Box-folder 56/8)
    - Savasta, J.
      - Le prince noir. Athens: M. Kazaze, n.d., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. M.118 K. (Box-folder 56/9)
    - Scarlatti, Alessandro
      - Già il sole dal Gange. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 53999.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/10)
      - O cessate di piagarmi. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 51928.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/11)
      - Se delitto è l'adorarvi. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 101937.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/12)
      - Se Florindo è fedele. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 51929.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/13)
      - Se tu della mia morte. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 51932.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/14)
      - Sento nel core. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 53997.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/15)
      - Son tutta duolo. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 51930.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/16)
      - Spesso vibra per suo gioco. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 51931.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/17)
      - Toglietemi la vita. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 101936.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 56/18)
    - Scarlatti, Domenico
      - 18 ausgewählte Klavierstücke. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Solo piano; score; 67 p.; Plate no. 8161.; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 56/19)
    - Schmitt, Florent
      - Le petit elfe "Ferme-l'oeil," op. 73. Paris: A. Durand, 1924., Reduction by the composer for solo piano; score; 54 p.; Plate no. D. & F.10436.; Contains holograph dedication to Diaghilev from the composer on title page. (Box-folder 56/20)
      - Pièces récréatives, op. 37. Paris: J. Hamelle, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 10 p.; Plate no. G.93 H. through G.95 H. (Box-folder 56/21)
    - Schreker, Franz
      - Der Geburtstag der Infantin: Tanz-Suite. Vienna: Universal, 1909., Reduction for piano, four hands; score; 35 p.; Plate no. U.E.2545. (Box-folder S/37)
    - Schubert, Franz
      - Berühmte Klavier-Compositionen. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Score; 153 p.; Plate no. 6260. (Box-folder S/57)
      - Compositionen. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Score; 111 p.; Plate no. 8376. (Box-folder S/57)
      - Sämmtliche Tänze. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Score; 74 p.; Plate no. 6696. (Box-folder S/57)
      - Sonaten. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Score; 222 p.; Plate no. 6700. (Box-folder S/57)
    - Schumann, Robert
      - Carnaval, op. 9. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 37 p.; Plate no. D. & F.9371.; Contents: BOX: 56/22 Copy 1: contains annotations in pencil in score; annotations in ink, reading: "Boris Zadim/25-I-1926" on title page and on cover. BOX: 56/23 Copy 2 of the above. (Box-folder 56/22-3)
    - Scotto, Marc-César
      - Rapsodie niçoise. Nice: Delrieu Frères, 1926., Arranged by the composer for solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. D.F.254.; Holograph dedication to Diaghilev from the composer on verso of title page. (Box-folder 56/24)
    - Seleznev, A.
      - Raznoshchik. Hamburg: F. Schuberth, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 868.; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 56/25)
    - Sellenick, A.
      - Marche indienne. Paris: A. Leduc, 1911., Arranged by the composer for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. A.L.6752. (Box-folder 56/26)
    - Senilov, Vladimir Alexeevich
      - Kalechina-malechina, op. 10, no. 2. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 37202.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 56/27)
      - Kolybel'naia piesnia, op. 10, no. 1. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 37201.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 56/28)
    - Shafrov, N. M.
      - Ne nado!...Ne nado! Petrograd: N. Davingof, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. N.1433 D.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 56/29)
    - Sharov, M.
      - Bielaia akatsiia. Moscow: S.IA. IAmbor, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 56/30)
    - Shtraus, Oskar
      - V vikhrie val'sa: V grëzakh. Moscow: S.IA. IAmbor, n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Solo piano score with vocal line indications, Russian lyrics; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 56/31)
    - Sibelius, Jean
      - Scaramouche, op. 71. Copenhagen: W. Hansen, 1919., Arranged by O. Olsen for solo piano; score; 73 p.; Plate no. 15827. (Box-folder 57/1)
      - Der Schwan von Tuonela, op. 22, no. 3. [Lemminkäinen Suite.] Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1907., Arranged by O. Taubmann for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 25771.; Published 1907/1935 (Box-folder 57/2)
      - Valse triste. [Kuolema, op. 44.] Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1904., Arranged for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. V.A.2224. (Box-folder 57/3)
    - Slavenski, Josip
      - Balkanophonia, op. 10. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1928., Full score; 51 p.; Plate no. 32190.; Composer also known by the name: Štolcer-Slavenski, Josip (Box-folder 57/4)
    - Slavini, Niccolo
      - Bosphore valse. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Possibly published in Constantinople by J. d'Andria. (Box-folder 57/5)
    - Smith, Melson
      - Romanza, A-flat major. Paris: Éditions Ricordi, 1921., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 2 p.; 4 p.; Plate no. 806.; Holograph dedication to Diaghilev from the composer on cover. (Box-folder 57/6)
    - Sokolov, Flaviĭ Vasil'evich
      - Tsyganskaia pies'nia (Sobiraities' dievki krasnyia). Hamburg: F. Schuberth, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 869.; Language note: German; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 57/7)
    - Somerville, Reginald
      - Fo'c'stle dance. London: Hawkes, 1929., Small orchestra; 4 p.; Plate no. 6740.; Contains annotations in pencil.; piano/conductor's score only. (Box-folder 57/8)
    - Spendiarov, Aleksandr Afanas'evich
      - Deux morceaux, op. 3: Berceuse. Paris: W. Bessel, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 5085. (Box-folder 57/9)
    - Spies, Leo
      - Apollo und Daphne. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Photoreproduced score [reduction ?] for solo piano; 34 p.; Includes 1 p. typescript and 1 p. photoreproduced synopsis, typed, of the ballet's action; in German. (Box-folder 57/10)
    - Stamper, Dave
      - Prends garde à Tchou-tchin-tchou. Constantinople: J. d'Andria, n.d., Arranged by F. Salabert for voice and piano; voice part, piano score; 2 p.; 5 p.; Plate no. 463.; Language note: French; Language note: English (Box-folder 57/11)
    - Slavenski, Josip
      - Semela, op. 10; Midas. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, n.d., Reduction for solo piano; score; [23] p.; Plate no. 3088.; Composer also known by the name: Shteĭnberg, Maksimilian Osseevich; Contents incomplete: Semela: p. 1 only Midas: p. 45 through 77 (Act II to the end) only; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder S/58)
    - Stivinskiĭ, S.
      - Gdie ty, milyĭ bozhok? Moscow: B.L. Andrzheevskiĭ, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. B.105 A.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 57/12)
    - Storoni, J.
      - Amapa. Paris: F. Salabert, 1913., Arranged for solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. E.A.S.576. (Box-folder 57/13)
    - Strauss, Johann
      - Johann Strauss' famous waltzes. London: K. Prowse, 1931., Arranged by E. Haywood for solo piano; score; 64 p.; Plate no. K.P. & Co.Ltd.4321.; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 57/14)
      - 10 valses célèbres. Paris: [A.] Durand, 1932., Arranged for solo piano; score; 95 p.; Plate no. D. & F.12190. (Box-folder 57/15)
    - Strauss, Richard
      - Schlagobers, op. 70. Berlin: A. Fürstner, 1923., Reduction by O. Singer for solo piano; score; 156 p.; Plate no. A.7752 F. (Box-folder 57/16)
      - Till Eulenspiegels lustige Streiche, op. 28. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1903., Arranged for solo piano; score; 26 p.; Plate no. 3056. (Box-folder 57/17)
    - Stravinsky, Igor
      - Le rossignol. Berlin: Édition russe de musique, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 93 p.; Plate no. R.M.V.241.; Language note: French; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 57/18)
      - A song of the dew, op. 6, no. 2 See: I.B. Collections, Box 4 (S/65), p. 69-70
    - Strimer, Joseph
      - Dans la rue: Au son du moteur. Paris: Rouart, n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Also published Paris: Lerolle, n.d.; Plate no. R.L.11915 (5) & Cie. (Box-folder 58/1)
      - Dans la rue: Catherinette. Paris: Rouart, n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Also published Paris: Lerolle, n.d.; Plate no. R.L.11915 (4) & Cie. (Box-folder 58/2)
      - Tempo di minuetto. Paris: J. Joubert, 1931., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. J.J.427. (Box-folder 58/3)
    - Suelto, Ramon
      - Créollita. Paris: Ramon Suelto, n.d., Solo piano; score; 2 p.; Plate no. 1.; Composer also known by the name: Allouche, Yvon (Box-folder 58/4)
    - Szymanowski, Karol
      - Cztery pieśni, op. 2, no. 3: We mgłach. Warsaw: Gebethner & Wolff, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. G 4927 W.; Language note: Polish; Language note: German (Box-folder 58/5)
      - Cztery pieśni, op. 2, no. 4: Czasem gdy długo na półsennie marzę. Warsaw: Gebethner & Wolff, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. G 4928 W.; Language note: Polish; Language note: German (Box-folder 58/6)
      - 9 preludes, op. 1, no. 1. Berlin: A. Stahl, 1906., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 10. (Box-folder 58/7)
    - Tansman, Alexandre
      - Bric-à-brac. Paris: M. Eschig, 1938., Reduction for solo piano; score; 58 p.; Plate no. M.E.9636. (Box-folder 58/8)
      - Sextuor. Paris: M. Eschig, 1929., Reduction for solo piano; score; 23 p.; Plate no. M.E.2377. (Box-folder 58/9)
    - Tartini, Giuseppe
      - Pastorale. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1921., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 5 p.; 11 p.; Plate no. E.R.267. (Box-folder 58/10)
      - Sonate, D major: 1. Grave-Allegro. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 2 p.; 5 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R. & Cie 176. (Box-folder 58/11)
      - Sonate, D major: 2. Larghetto. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 1 p.; 3 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R. & Cie 177. (Box-folder 58/12)
      - Sonate, D major: 3. Gigue. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 1 p.; 3 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R. & Cie 178. (Box-folder 58/13)
      - Sonate, E major. Paris: M. Senart, 1917., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 4 p.; 12 p.; Plate no. M.S. & Cie.5208. (Box-folder 58/14)
    - Tchaikovsky, Pëtr Il'ich
      - La belle au bois dormant, op. 66, no. 24 See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
      - Berceuse, op. 16, no. 1. Paris: A. Noël, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. M. & N.2016.No.1-(2).; Language note: French (Box-folder 58/15)
      - Casse-noisette, op. 71. [=Shchelkunchik; The Nutcracker.] Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Reduction by the composer for solo piano; score; 166 p.; Plate no. 17782.; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 58/16)
      - Casse-noisette, op. 71: Suite. London: W. Reeves, n.d., Arranged by E. Evans for solo piano; score; 42 p.; Plate no. W.R.84. (Box-folder 58/17)